Abdullah Al Mamun

 \searrow

lin





Qualifications and Interests

Highly motivated in animal science, biomedical research, big data analysis, computational biology and one health. Research experience in designing and implementing projects to solve critical problems and research focus mindset. My research approach includes animal production, genetics, antibiotics resistance, big data in healthcare, population-based studies, and one health.

Research Experiences

OMICS-CENTER(Chiral) Bangladesh

Gene-Analyst and Project Associate

Dhaka, Bangladesh January2024 - Present

· Application and analysis of bioinformatics tools to identify pattern and trends of genetic data

Center for Health Innovation, Research, Action, and Learning - Bangladesh

Research Intern & Project Associate

Dhaka, Bangladesh

October 2023 - Present • Develop and communicate among intern, training and collaboration of the organization

· Data Analyst, Technical Supporter

Unicode IT Dhaka, Bangladesh

Junior Data Analyst, Lead Generation Expert July 2023 - September 2023

· Coordinator, Advisor

· Participated in fieldwork, including data collection and data entry

Blackbaud Dhaka, Bangladesh

DATA ENUMERATOR April2021 - May 2022

• Formation of new conception, critical situation handling, operation builder

Education and Training

Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Science & Technology University, Gopalganj-8100

Bachelor in Science in Veterinary Science & Animal Husbandry

Dhaka, Bangladesh January 2019 - Present

Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Science & Technology University, Gopalganj-8100

EDGE-BSMRSTUCSE Digital Skills Training

Dhaka, Bangladesh April 2024 - Present

IPB University, Indonesia

The International Summer Course: One Health Concept for Tropical Diseases Mitigation

Dhaka, Bangladesh 19 July 2022-7August 2022

Helix KU-Biotech

Workshop on Adobe Illustrator

Khulna, Bangladesh 18 August -19August 2020

CEVETBD Conference

Virtual Conference

Dhaka, Bangladesh 19-23December2020

1

Abdullah Al Mamun - CV

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, R, **Data Science:** scikit-learn, Pycharm, Dask, PySpark; **Analytics Softwares:** SPSS, Microsoft Ex-cel; **Survey Tools:** KoboToolBox, EpiCollect, Google Forms; **Academic Writing Tools:** Microsoft Word, LaTeX, Mende-ley; **Bioinformatics:** BioPython, BioPandas, BioConductor; **CancerResearchTools:** GEO2, ULCAN, GEPIA2, TIMER, TCGA; **Miscellaneous Skills:** RStudio, Jupyter, VSCode, Rmarkdown, Quarto, Lead-Generator, SEO.

Projects

RESEARCH

Bacteriophages Significance Against Antibiotic-Resistant Bacterial Infections An One Health Approach

ROLE: Co-author, Research Assistant

Timeline
June 2023 - Present

Significant gene expression of Lung Adenocarcinoma Disease in Living Organism

ROLE: Co-author, Manuscript writing

Timeline
March 2024 -Present

Significant gene expression of Lung Adenocarcinoma Disease in Living Organism

ROLE: Principal Investigator, Project Assistant

Timeline August 2023 -Present

Environmental effects on cross breed cattle of frequent prevalence diseases in Southeast Bangladesh

ROLE: Project Investigator, Study Design

Timeline February2024 -Present

Heat Stress Effects on Dairy Cattle

Timeline

ROLE: Paper Contributor, Data Analysis

July 2023 - Present

Courses and Workshops

2023-24 **R for Research**: Internship (CHIRAL, Bangladesh)

The purpose of this course is to provide a practical introduction to the programming language R for researchers in any field.

2023-24 **R for Bioinformatics**: Internship (CHIRAL, Bangladesh)

In this course, participants will explore the application of the R programming language in the field of bioinformatics.

2023-24 **Clinical Reporting Using gt-summary**: Internship (CHIRAL Bangladesh)

A one-day workshop on publication-ready tables using gt-summary package in R.

- 2023 **Machine Learning for Bioinformatics with Python**: The course equips participants with essential machine-learning skills to solve bioinformatics problems.
- 2023-24 **Data Analysis with R**: Learner (CHIRAL Bangladesh)

The purpose of this course is to provide a practical introduction to the programming language R for researchers in any field.

2023 **RNA-seq Data Analysis with R**: Learner (CHIRAL Bangladesh)

This course empowers participants to proficiently analyze and interpret RNA-seq data using R.

- 2023 **DNA/RNA-Seq Analysis, Mutation Identification by use of BLAST**: Learner (Dr. Muhammad Naveed)
 - This course caters to researchers and bioinformaticians aiming to find coding errors and interpret the result
- 2023 **Research Data Analysis with SPSS**: Learner (CHIRAL Bangladesh, Bangladesh)

This course is tailored for researchers, analysts, and students seeking a strong foundation in utilizing SPSS for data analysis in research projects.

References

Dr.Hoor-E-Jannat

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR, DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL SCIENCE & VETERINARY MEDICINE, BANGABANDHU SHEIKH MUJIBUR RAHMAN SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY, GOPALGANJ-8100

• Email:jaoti52@gmail.com

Dr.Marzia Afroze Priya

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR, DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL SCIENCE & VETERINARY MEDICINE, BANGABANDHU SHEIKH MUJIBUR RAHMAN SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY, GOPALGANJ-8100

• Email:marziapriya22@gmail.com

Md.Sharifuzzaman

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR, DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL SCIENCE & VETERINARY MEDICINE, BANGABANDHU SHEIKH MUJIBUR RAHMAN SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY, GOPALGANJ-8100

• Email:baushossain@gmail.com